<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.4">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://ysnrski.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><link href="https://ysnrski.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en"/><updated>2025-07-30T09:23:43+00:00</updated><id>https://ysnrski.github.io/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Yasu Sakai</title><subtitle>A simple, whitespace theme for academics. Based on [*folio](https://github.com/bogoli/-folio) design. </subtitle><entry><title type="html">What is Friction?</title><link href="https://ysnrski.github.io/blog/2025/What-is-Friction/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="What is Friction?"/><published>2025-02-20T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-02-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://ysnrski.github.io/blog/2025/What%20is%20Friction</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://ysnrski.github.io/blog/2025/What-is-Friction/"><![CDATA[<p>Friction, a force that resists the relative motion of two objects in contact, is a fundamental phenomenon that affects many engineering systems. However, the interaction of friction with materials and motion can sometimes be far from straightforward. In particular, friction can exhibit nonlinear characteristics, causing unexpected behaviour in precision systems such as machine tools and semiconductor equipment.</p> <h2 id="what-is-friction">What Is Friction?</h2> <p>Friction is the force that resists the sliding motion of objects in contact. Historically, the theory of friction has evolved through various models. Early theories, like the <em>asperity model</em>, explain friction as the result of microscopic surface roughness that leads to mechanical interlocking. Modern research looks deeper, focusing on molecular interactions and the behaviours that emerge under different conditions.</p> <p>In simple terms, friction arises from the contact between surfaces and is characterized by the coefficient of friction. This coefficient is influenced by factors like surface roughness, material properties, and lubrication. The fascinating aspect of friction is that it’s not always linear, especially under varying conditions like speed, pressure, and temperature.</p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/posts/20250220/Schematic-of-a-typical-friction-coefficient-showing-static-and-kinetic-friction-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/posts/20250220/Schematic-of-a-typical-friction-coefficient-showing-static-and-kinetic-friction-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/posts/20250220/Schematic-of-a-typical-friction-coefficient-showing-static-and-kinetic-friction-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/posts/20250220/Schematic-of-a-typical-friction-coefficient-showing-static-and-kinetic-friction.png" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <p>Schematic of a typical friction behavior: image source <a href="http://dx.doi.org/10.1115/1.2768074">Andreas A, Journal of Tribology, 2007</a></p> <h2 id="what-happens-when-friction-becomes-nonlinear">What Happens When Friction Becomes Nonlinear?</h2> <p>The term “nonlinear friction” refers to friction forces that do not follow a straightforward, predictable relationship with the motion of the objects in contact. For example, in some mechanical systems, the frictional force may increase suddenly when the relative speed changes or when the pressure at the contact point increases.</p> <p>This nonlinear behaviour is especially important in high-precision systems components like linear guides or bearings, where even minor variations in friction can cause significant deviations in the system’s performance. The friction may behave like a spring (or a nonlinear spring), where it resists movement, but the resistance doesn’t follow a simple linear law.</p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/posts/20250220/F3-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/posts/20250220/F3-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/posts/20250220/F3-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/posts/20250220/F3.png" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <p>Nonlinear Spring behavior, image source: <a href="https://www.intechopen.com/chapters/73645">Yasunori S, Tribology in Materials and Manufacturing - Wear, Friction and Lubrication</a></p> <h2 id="why-does-friction-act-like-a-spring">Why Does Friction Act Like a Spring?</h2> <p>Due to the way surfaces interact at a microscopic level, friction can behave like a spring under certain conditions. When two surfaces slide against each other, they often experience microscopic adhesive forces that can suddenly “snap” as they overcome surface asperities. This can create a kind of “spring-like” effect in the frictional resistance.</p> <p>This spring-like effect is most noticeable when there is a significant variation in velocity or pressure, and it can be particularly troubling in systems that require precise control. The nonlinear nature of this friction means that standard models, which assume linear resistance, can fail to predict system behaviour accurately.</p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/posts/20250220/Typical-wear-modes-of-surface-asperities-under-low-angle-collision-Wear-mode-of-ductile-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/posts/20250220/Typical-wear-modes-of-surface-asperities-under-low-angle-collision-Wear-mode-of-ductile-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/posts/20250220/Typical-wear-modes-of-surface-asperities-under-low-angle-collision-Wear-mode-of-ductile-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/posts/20250220/Typical-wear-modes-of-surface-asperities-under-low-angle-collision-Wear-mode-of-ductile.png" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <p>Mechanisms of adhesion, elastic/plastic deformation and wear, image source: <a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-020-57429-5">Andrey V. Dimaki, et. al., Scientific Reports</a></p> <h2 id="practical-examples-in-precision-systems">Practical Examples in Precision Systems</h2> <p>In precision engineering, components such as linear guides and bearings often experience nonlinear friction. As these components move at varying speeds or under fluctuating loads, the friction they generate can change unexpectedly. For example, at low speeds, the friction might behave almost like a spring, offering smooth resistance. However, at higher speeds, it may become more irregular, leading to sudden jumps in resistance.</p> <p>This nonlinearity is problematic for systems requiring high precision, such as robotic arms, CNC machines, or other motion control systems. Small variations in friction can lead to inaccuracies in positioning and even cause oscillations, which can degrade the entire system’s performance.</p> <h2 id="nonlinear-frictions-impact-on-control-systems">Nonlinear Friction’s Impact on Control Systems</h2> <p>The unpredictable nature of nonlinear friction can introduce major challenges for control systems. For example, in robotics or high-precision manufacturing, controlling motion with high accuracy requires precise knowledge of all forces acting on the system – including friction. When friction behaves unpredictably, it makes it difficult to predict how the system will respond to control inputs, leading to overshooting, oscillations, or even instability.</p> <p>Engineers/researchers often use friction compensation techniques to mitigate these issues. These methods involve creating mathematical models to predict the friction force based on factors like velocity, pressure, and temperature and then adjusting the control inputs to counteract the friction’s impact.</p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/posts/20250220/images_tcsme-2023-0168_f14-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/posts/20250220/images_tcsme-2023-0168_f14-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/posts/20250220/images_tcsme-2023-0168_f14-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/posts/20250220/images_tcsme-2023-0168_f14.jpg" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <p>Error in motion trajectory in CNC machine due to nonlinear friction, image source: <a href="https://doi.org/10.1139/tcsme-2023-0168">Yuheng Zhu et.al., Transaction of the Canadian Society for Mechanical Engineering</a></p> <h2 id="how-to-control-nonlinear-friction">How to Control Nonlinear Friction?</h2> <p>Despite its complexity, researchers have been working on ways to model and control nonlinear friction. Some advanced control systems use real-time data to estimate the frictional forces and adjust accordingly. Machine learning is also being explored as a way to predict friction behaviour more accurately, especially in systems with many variabilities.</p> <p>For example, friction compensation control methods can significantly improve system performance by continuously adjusting the motor inputs to counteract friction’s effect. Machine learning algorithms can also be used to train models that predict friction behaviour based on data collected during operation.</p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/posts/20250220/1-s2.0-S0019057821000227-gr13-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/posts/20250220/1-s2.0-S0019057821000227-gr13-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/posts/20250220/1-s2.0-S0019057821000227-gr13-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/posts/20250220/1-s2.0-S0019057821000227-gr13.jpg" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <p>Nolinear Friction compensation with estimator (Mathmatical model of friction), image source: <a href="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.isatra.2021.01.020">Mohammad J F., et. al., ISA Transactions</a></p> <h2 id="conclusion-making-the-most-of-nonlinear-friction">Conclusion: Making the Most of Nonlinear Friction</h2> <p>By understanding and leveraging friction’s nonlinear nature, engineers can improve the precision and performance of systems that rely on smooth, controlled motion. When carefully managed, nonlinear friction can be used as an advantage—much like a spring. It can provide predictable resistance that enhances system stability and accuracy.</p> <p>As the field of friction modelling continues to evolve, there are increasing opportunities to refine these techniques and apply them to a wide range of applications, from manufacturing and robotics to consumer electronics. The key is to recognize that friction is not just a resistance force; it can be harnessed and controlled to achieve better performance and reliability in complex systems.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="insight"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Friction, a force that resists the relative motion of two objects in contact, is a fundamental phenomenon that affects many engineering systems. However, the interaction of friction with materials and motion can sometimes be far from straightforward.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Machine tool industry</title><link href="https://ysnrski.github.io/blog/2025/Machine-Tool-Industry/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Machine tool industry"/><published>2025-02-13T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-02-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://ysnrski.github.io/blog/2025/Machine%20Tool%20Industry</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://ysnrski.github.io/blog/2025/Machine-Tool-Industry/"><![CDATA[]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Overview of japan professional engineer pe qualification</title><link href="https://ysnrski.github.io/blog/2025/Overview-of-Japan-Professional-Engineer-PE-Qualification/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Overview of japan professional engineer pe qualification"/><published>2025-02-12T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-02-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://ysnrski.github.io/blog/2025/Overview%20of%20Japan%20Professional%20Engineer%20PE%20Qualification</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://ysnrski.github.io/blog/2025/Overview-of-Japan-Professional-Engineer-PE-Qualification/"><![CDATA[]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Paper Review - An Investigation on Utilizing Large Language Model for Industrial Computer-Aided Design Automation</title><link href="https://ysnrski.github.io/blog/2025/Paper-Review-An-Investigation-on-Utilizing-Large-Language-Model-for-Industrial/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Paper Review - An Investigation on Utilizing Large Language Model for Industrial Computer-Aided Design Automation"/><published>2025-02-10T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-02-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://ysnrski.github.io/blog/2025/Paper%20Review%20-%20An%20Investigation%20on%20Utilizing%20Large%20Language%20Model%20for%20Industrial</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://ysnrski.github.io/blog/2025/Paper-Review-An-Investigation-on-Utilizing-Large-Language-Model-for-Industrial/"><![CDATA[<p>Recently, the weather in Suzhou, Taicang, has turned colder. As a result, I’ve been biking to work less often and relying more on public buses for my daily commute.</p> <h3 id="revolutionizing-cad-with-natural-language-commands">Revolutionizing CAD with Natural Language Commands</h3> <p>Imagine designing complex industrial components like gears, shafts, or machinery parts by simply typing instructions in plain natural language like English. This paper explores how <strong>large language models (LLMs) like GPT-4</strong> can automate tedious engineering computations and generate precise 3D CAD models, bridging the gap between human creativity and AI-driven precision.</p> <h3 id="original-paper">Original Paper</h3> <p>Haoxuan Deng, Samir Khan, John Ahmet Erkoyuncu, An Investigation on Utilizing Large Language Model for Industrial Computer-Aided Design Automation, Procedia CIRP, Vol. 128, pp 221-226 (2024), <a href="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.procir.2024.07.049">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.procir.2024.07.049</a></p> <p>All figures and tables in this post are cited from the respective papers.</p> <h3 id="key-innovations"><strong>Key Innovations</strong></h3> <ol> <li><strong>From Text to 3D Models</strong> <ul> <li>Current generative AI (e.g., text-to-image tools) struggles with industrial CAD due to randomness and lack of control.</li> <li>This research uses <strong>GPT-4</strong> to translate natural language requirements into <strong>parametric calculations</strong> (e.g., gear ratios, dimensions) and <strong>OpenSCAD scripts</strong>, producing editable, production-ready 3D models.</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Workflow Automation</strong> <ul> <li><strong>Step 1:</strong> Users input design requirements (e.g., “Design a gear system with a 5:1 ratio”).</li> <li><strong>Step 2:</strong> GPT-4 computes parameters (module size, teeth count) and generates a structured JSON file.</li> <li><strong>Step 3:</strong> The model writes code for OpenSCAD, a programmable CAD tool, to render precise 3D geometries.</li> </ul> </li> </ol> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/posts/20250210/image-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/posts/20250210/image-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/posts/20250210/image-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/posts/20250210/image.png" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/posts/20250210/image%201-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/posts/20250210/image%201-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/posts/20250210/image%201-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/posts/20250210/image%201.png" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <ol> <li><strong>Human-AI Collaboration</strong> <ul> <li>Engineers review and tweak results at every stage, ensuring alignment with industrial standards.</li> <li>The system supports iterative refinement, reducing errors from AI “hallucinations” while saving time on repetitive tasks.</li> </ul> </li> </ol> <hr/> <h3 id="proof-of-concept-gear-system-design"><strong>Proof of Concept: Gear System Design</strong></h3> <p>The paper demonstrates the method with a <strong>single-stage reduction gear system</strong>:</p> <ul> <li>GPT-4 successfully computed parameters (gear module, teeth count, coordinates) from text prompts.</li> <li>Generated OpenSCAD scripts and produced accurate 3D models for spur, helical, and herringbone gears (see images in the paper).</li> <li>Outputs are fully editable in standard CAD environments, enabling customization without format conversions.</li> </ul> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/posts/20250210/image%202-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/posts/20250210/image%202-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/posts/20250210/image%202-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/posts/20250210/image%202.png" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <hr/> <h3 id="key-contribution">Key Contribution</h3> <ol> <li><strong>Faster Design Cycles</strong> <ul> <li>Automate calculations and model generation, cutting hours of manual work.</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Accessible Innovation</strong> <ul> <li>Lower the barrier for non-experts to prototype complex designs using natural language.</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Scalable Precision</strong> <ul> <li>Integrate with existing tools like OpenSCAD or SolidWorks, ensuring compatibility with industrial workflows.</li> </ul> </li> </ol> <hr/> <h3 id="future-vision"><strong>Future Vision</strong></h3> <p>The authors outline exciting next steps:</p> <ul> <li><strong>Complex Assemblies</strong>: Extend to multi-component systems (bearings, shafts, housings).</li> <li><strong>Multi-Agent Collaboration</strong>: Deploy LLM “agents” to simulate cross-disciplinary teams (e.g., integrating supply chain data).</li> <li><strong>Advanced CAD Techniques</strong>: Support generative design and topology optimization.</li> </ul> <hr/> <p>Imagine a future where anyone can design industrial parts as easily as writing an email. Let’s build the next generation of CAD tools together.</p> <p><strong>Ready to revolutionize design?</strong> Stay tuned to my blog, and connect with my X and Linkedin!</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="review"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Paper Review - An Investigation on Utilizing Large Language Model for Industrial Computer-Aided Design Automation]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Design Innovation - AI-Generated CAD vs NLP Interactive CAD</title><link href="https://ysnrski.github.io/blog/2025/Design-Innovation-AI-Generated-CAD-vs-NLP-Interactive-CAD/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Design Innovation - AI-Generated CAD vs NLP Interactive CAD"/><published>2025-02-08T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-02-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://ysnrski.github.io/blog/2025/Design%20Innovation%20AI-Generated%20CAD%20vs%20NLP%20Interactive%20CAD</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://ysnrski.github.io/blog/2025/Design-Innovation-AI-Generated-CAD-vs-NLP-Interactive-CAD/"><![CDATA[<h3 id="1-understanding-ai-generated-cad-design">1. Understanding AI-Generated CAD Design</h3> <p>AI-generated CAD is a cutting-edge approach to design automation. It utilizes machine learning and deep learning to identify patterns from existing design data. Based on this knowledge, it can autonomously generate new designs with minimal human intervention. Techniques such as Generative Adversarial Networks (GANs) and Variational Autoencoders (VAEs) are commonly used in these systems.</p> <h3 id="key-technical-elements">Key Technical Elements:</h3> <ul> <li><strong>Generative Models:</strong> GANs and VAEs play a central role in generating new design ideas by learning from large datasets of existing designs. These models help produce innovative structures and shapes that are often beyond the scope of conventional design methods.</li> </ul> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/posts/20250208/11263_2020_1335_Fig1_HTML.webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/posts/20250208/11263_2020_1335_Fig1_HTML.webp" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <p>GAN algorithm for 3D shape generation, image source: <a href="https://link.springer.com/article/10.1007/s11263-020-01335-w">Matheus. G., et al (2020)</a></p> <ul> <li><strong>Topology Optimization:</strong> AI-powered CAD systems can apply topology optimization, which involves maximizing performance while minimizing material usage based on desired objective functions. This is particularly valuable in industries such as aerospace and automotive, where lightweight, high-performance structures are critical.</li> </ul> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/posts/20250208/1-s2.0-S1000936120304520-gr3-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/posts/20250208/1-s2.0-S1000936120304520-gr3-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/posts/20250208/1-s2.0-S1000936120304520-gr3-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/posts/20250208/1-s2.0-S1000936120304520-gr3.jpg" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <p>Toporogy optimization process and CAM based CNC machining. image source: <a href="https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S1000936120304520">Jihong, Z., et al. (2021)</a></p> <h3 id="advantages">Advantages:</h3> <ul> <li><strong>Time and Effort Savings:</strong> AI-driven automation significantly reduces the time and labour involved in generating designs, especially when dealing with complex systems or large datasets.</li> <li><strong>Multidimensional Optimization:</strong> AI can simultaneously optimize multiple design parameters, including strength, weight, and material usage, to achieve the most efficient outcomes.</li> </ul> <h3 id="challenges">Challenges:</h3> <ul> <li><strong>Data Dependence:</strong> AI’s ability to generate creative designs is constrained by the quality and diversity of the data it is trained on. Without sufficient variety in the training data, AI may fail to propose truly novel ideas.</li> <li><strong>Lack of Interpretability:</strong> A major challenge with AI-generated CAD is its “black-box” nature. The designs produced by AI may be difficult to interpret or explain, which can pose a barrier in fields that require clear decision-making and traceability.</li> <li><strong>Feature Dependencies and Sequential Design:</strong> Traditional CAD relies on sequential 2D sketches and extrusions to form 3D shapes. During this process, the creation of features like bodies, faces, lines, and points often depends on a specific order. This structured order plays an essential role in managing and modifying designs. In contrast, AI-generated designs are typically represented as collections of discrete data points, such as voxels or point clouds, which may not follow these established dependencies. As a result, many AI-generated models lack the intuitive structure required for effective refinement in traditional CAD workflows. However, methods that incorporate sketch-based learning have been proposed to address this issue, though they are still in the development phase.</li> </ul> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/posts/20250208/download-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/posts/20250208/download-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/posts/20250208/download-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/posts/20250208/download.jpg" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <p>Extrusion process of CAD operation process, image source: <a href="https://www.designworkshopsydney.com.au/autocad-3d-extrude/">Design Workshop Sydney</a></p> <hr/> <h3 id="2-the-role-of-nlp-in-interactive-cad-design">2. The Role of NLP in Interactive CAD Design</h3> <p>Natural Language Processing (NLP) enables more intuitive interactions within CAD systems. By allowing users to issue commands in natural language, these systems can interpret the instructions and generate or modify 3D models accordingly. My blog post about NLP-based CAD is available for further basic information (Blog post: <a href="https://ysnrski.github.io/blog/2025/The-Future-of-3D-CAD-Design-with-Natural-Language/">The Future of 3D CAD Design with Natural Language Processing</a><strong>)</strong></p> <h3 id="key-technical-elements-1">Key Technical Elements:</h3> <ul> <li><strong>Natural Language Understanding:</strong> Large language models (LLMs) such as GPT-4, DeepSeek, and BERT understand user commands. For instance, a user might instruct the system with a sentence like <em>“Create a central tower of 80 m in height, surrounded by four smaller towers, each with a radius of 12 m, placed in four directions.”</em> These systems can parse the language and convert it into executable CAD instructions.</li> </ul> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/posts/20250208/image-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/posts/20250208/image-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/posts/20250208/image-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/posts/20250208/image.png" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <p>LLM baesd interaction with CAD system, image source: <a href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2406.00144">Akshay B., et al (2024)</a></p> <ul> <li><strong>Code Generation:</strong> Once the natural language input is understood, the system generates the corresponding CAD code to realize the user’s design. This seamless interaction makes CAD systems more accessible to people without technical expertise.</li> </ul> <h3 id="advantages-1">Advantages:</h3> <ul> <li><strong>User-Friendliness:</strong> NLP-based CAD systems make it easier for non-experts to engage in design by allowing them to express their ideas through natural language, removing the need for detailed technical knowledge.</li> <li><strong>Faster Prototyping:</strong> NLP enhances the ability to quickly generate or modify models, speeding up the design process and making rapid iteration more feasible.</li> <li><strong>Integration with VR/AR:</strong> NLP-based CAD systems hold great potential for integration with Virtual Reality (VR) and Augmented Reality (AR). This would enable immersive design experiences where users can interact with and modify models in a 3D virtual space (Cyberspace), offering more intuitive and engaging design workflows. Also, the generated models would easily be utilized for digital twin simulation in manufacturing processes or product characteristics.</li> </ul> <h3 id="challenges-1">Challenges:</h3> <ul> <li><strong>Ambiguity in Language:</strong> Natural language can be inherently ambiguous, leading to potential misinterpretations of design instructions. For instance, a phrase like <em>“Make the design thinner”</em> could be understood in various ways depending on context.</li> <li><strong>Complexity of Expression:</strong> While simple designs can be easily described, more intricate design commands may be difficult to articulate effectively in natural language, which may require advancements in NLP technology.</li> </ul> <hr/> <h3 id="3-comparing-ai-generated-cad-and-nlp-interactive-cad">3. Comparing AI-Generated CAD and NLP Interactive CAD</h3> <table> <thead> <tr> <th><strong>Aspect</strong></th> <th><strong>AI-Generated CAD</strong></th> <th><strong>NLP Interactive CAD</strong></th> </tr> </thead> <tbody> <tr> <td><strong>Automation Level</strong></td> <td>High (AI autonomously generates designs)</td> <td>Moderate (based on user input)</td> </tr> <tr> <td><strong>User Involvement</strong></td> <td>Low (minimal human interaction)</td> <td>High (active user participation)</td> </tr> <tr> <td><strong>Creativity</strong></td> <td>Data-dependent (innovation is constrained)</td> <td>Reflects user creativity</td> </tr> <tr> <td><strong>Application Scope</strong></td> <td>Well-suited for data-intensive fields</td> <td>Applicable across diverse domains</td> </tr> <tr> <td><strong>Technical Challenges</strong></td> <td>Black-box nature, low interpretability</td> <td>Ambiguity in natural language</td> </tr> <tr> <td><strong>Feature Dependency</strong></td> <td>Lacks feature dependency awareness, leading to disjointed designs</td> <td>Maintains user-defined feature structure</td> </tr> <tr> <td><strong>Integration Potential</strong></td> <td>Limited integration with existing CAD workflows</td> <td>Easy integration with traditional CAD systems and VR/AR applications</td> </tr> </tbody> </table> <hr/> <h3 id="4-conclusion-the-need-for-integration-of-both-ai-and-nlp">4. Conclusion: The Need for Integration of Both AI and NLP</h3> <p>AI and NLP each bring unique strengths to the world of CAD design. AI excels at generating innovative designs based on existing data, offering efficient, optimized results that would be challenging for humans to conceive. However, the design process is inherently tied to human creativity and problem-solving. While AI can assist, it cannot replace the human touch in refining designs to meet practical and aesthetic goals.</p> <p>NLP-based systems, on the other hand, provide a more interactive and intuitive design experience. They make design accessible to users with little technical expertise and can speed up the prototyping process. Moreover, NLP can preserve the feature dependencies and the logical flow that is crucial in traditional CAD workflows, making it easier for human users to guide and refine designs.</p> <p>Both approaches have their merits, and neither is inherently superior to the other. The future of CAD design lies in the integration of AI’s generative power with NLP’s interactive capabilities. By combining these methods, we can create more efficient, intuitive, and accessible design tools that empower both expert designers and non-technical users alike.</p> <ul> <li>Please share your thoughts via comment or email!</li> <li>Follow my social media (LinkedIn, X), which will provide you with the latest blog posts!</li> </ul>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="insight"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Discover how AI and NLP are reshaping CAD systems! From automated design to natural language interfaces, learn about the future of design tools.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Studying STEM in Japan - A Guide for International Students</title><link href="https://ysnrski.github.io/blog/2025/Studying-STEM-in-Japan-A-Guide-for-International-Students/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Studying STEM in Japan - A Guide for International Students"/><published>2025-02-07T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-02-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://ysnrski.github.io/blog/2025/%20Studying%20STEM%20in%20Japan:%20A%20Guide%20for%20International%20Students</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://ysnrski.github.io/blog/2025/Studying-STEM-in-Japan-A-Guide-for-International-Students/"><![CDATA[<p>I received a question about this topic on social media, so I’ve summarized it in this post. Although my experience working at Japanese educational institutions was a few years ago, and preparation methods vary by university, this post will be a helpful starting point for every student. But if you would like to study with me, please consider Chinese university instead, specifically <a href="https://www.xjtlu.edu.cn/en">XJTLU</a>!!</p> <h2 id="introduction">Introduction</h2> <p>Japan offers opportunities for STEM (Science, Technology, Engineering, and Mathematics) education through its diverse higher education institutions. Understanding the structure of Japan’s educational system, the types of universities available, and unique institutions like “Kosen” (a Five-year college system enrolling after graduating from junior high school) is crucial for international students considering studying in Japan. This post provides an overview of Japan’s STEM education system and key insights based on my experiences.</p> <h2 id="types-of-higher-education-institutions-in-japan">Types of Higher Education Institutions in Japan</h2> <h3 id="1-national-universities">1. National Universities</h3> <ul> <li>Funded and operated by the Japanese government.</li> <li>Lower tuition fees compared to private universities.</li> <li>Various scholarship opportunities for international students.</li> <li>Examples: <a href="https://www.u-tokyo.ac.jp/en/prospective-students/prospective_students.html">University of Tokyo, Kyoto University</a>, <a href="https://www.tohoku.ac.jp/en/admissions/index.html">Tohoku University,</a> <a href="https://admissions.isct.ac.jp/en">Tokyo Institute of Technology (Institute of Science Tokyo)</a>.</li> </ul> <h3 id="2-public-prefectural-and-municipal-universities">2. Public (Prefectural and Municipal) Universities</h3> <ul> <li>Funded by local governments (Eg, Osaka prefecture, Yokohama City).</li> <li>More affordable tuition compared to private universities.</li> <li>Examples: <a href="https://www.osakafu-u.ac.jp/en/admission/">Osaka Prefecture University</a>, <a href="https://www-user.yokohama-cu.ac.jp/~english/index.php/admissions/">Yokohama City University</a>.</li> </ul> <h3 id="3-private-universities">3. Private Universities</h3> <ul> <li>Privately funded and managed.</li> <li>Vary in reputation, facilities, and research capabilities.</li> <li>Higher tuition fees, but modern facilities.</li> <li>Examples: <a href="https://www.keio.ac.jp/en/admissions/">Keio University</a>, <a href="https://www.waseda.jp/inst/admission/en/">Waseda University</a>, <a href="https://www.tus.ac.jp/en/admissions">Tokyo University of Science</a>, <a href="https://www.shibaura-it.ac.jp/en/study/index.html">Shibaura Institute of Technology</a>.</li> </ul> <h3 id="4-kosen">4. <strong>Kosen</strong></h3> <ul> <li><a href="https://www.kosen-k.go.jp/en/nationwide/educational_system">Unique five-year programs</a> integrating secondary and tertiary education, specializing in engineering and applied sciences.</li> <li>Graduates can enter the workforce or transfer to a university.</li> <li>Known for producing highly skilled engineers with practical experience.</li> <li>Offer an <strong>Associate Degree</strong>, though recognition may vary globally.</li> </ul> <h2 id="features-of-japans-stem-education-system">Features of Japan’s STEM Education System</h2> <h3 id="strong-emphasis-on-fundamental-sciences">Strong Emphasis on Fundamental Sciences</h3> <ul> <li>Japanese STEM programs focus heavily on mathematics and foundational sciences before specialization.</li> <li>Students develop strong theoretical knowledge before research or practical application.</li> </ul> <h3 id="a-research-thesis-is-mandatory-for-graduation">A research thesis is mandatory for graduation</h3> <ul> <li>4th-grade undergrad, Master’s, and Ph.D. students engage in rigorous research projects by belonging to specific laboratories.</li> <li>Most students must write a research thesis and conduct an oral defence presentation.</li> </ul> <h3 id="industry-collaboration-and-practical-training">Industry Collaboration and Practical Training</h3> <ul> <li>Many universities have strong industry ties, providing internships and employment opportunities.</li> <li>Engineering and technology students often work on industry-sponsored/government-sponsored projects.</li> </ul> <h2 id="choosing-a-university-in-japan">Choosing a University in Japan</h2> <h3 id="1-choosing-a-university-for-undergraduate-studies">1. Choosing a University for Undergraduate Studies</h3> <p><strong>Key Factors:</strong></p> <ul> <li><strong>Program Availability:</strong> Check if the university offers English-taught STEM programs (e.g., Shibaura Institute of Technology offers a program from which students can graduate using only English).</li> <li><strong>Research and Facilities:</strong> National universities generally have better research facilities, while private universities offer modern campuses and strong industry links.</li> <li><strong>Tuition &amp; Scholarships:</strong> National and public universities charge lower tuition fees, and scholarships like <a href="https://www.studyinjapan.go.jp/en/planning/scholarships/mext-scholarships/">MEXT</a> and <a href="https://www.jasso.go.jp/en/ryugaku/scholarship_j/index.html">JASSO</a> are available.</li> </ul> <p><strong>Career Paths:</strong></p> <ul> <li><strong>Entering the workforce:</strong> Opportunities in automotive, electronics, and robotics industries.</li> <li><strong>Continuing to a master’s program:</strong> Many engineering graduates pursue a master’s degree from national universities to increase job opportunities and salary potential.</li> </ul> <h3 id="2-choosing-a-university-for-graduate-studies">2. Choosing a University for Graduate Studies</h3> <p><strong>Key Factors:</strong></p> <ul> <li><strong>Supervisor and Research Lab:</strong> Choosing a graduate school in Japan is about finding the right professor and lab.</li> <li><strong>Research vs. Coursework:</strong> Most STEM programs are research-oriented but include coursework.</li> <li><strong>Scholarships &amp; Funding:</strong> MEXT, university scholarships, and industry partnerships provide financial support. Most universities provide scholarship databases for students (Example: <a href="https://www.titech.ac.jp/english/students/tuition/scholarships">Tokyo Tech</a>)</li> </ul> <p><strong>Career Paths:</strong></p> <ul> <li>Joining high-tech industries (R&amp;D engineer, AI specialist, materials scientist, etc.).</li> <li>Continuing to a Ph.D. for advanced research opportunities.</li> </ul> <h3 id="3-choosing-a-university-for-doctoral-studies">3. Choosing a University for Doctoral Studies</h3> <p><strong>Key Factors:</strong></p> <ul> <li><strong>Research Reputation:</strong> Japan excels in robotics, materials science, and renewable energy. Top universities include the University of Tokyo, Tokyo Institute of Technology, Kyoto University, and Tohoku University.</li> <li><strong>Funding Opportunities:</strong> Ph.D. students can receive research assistant (RA) positions, MEXT funding, industry-sponsored support, or a <a href="https://www.jsps.go.jp/english/e-pd/index.html">JSPE research fellowship(DC1/DC2)</a>.</li> <li><strong>Career Paths:</strong> <ul> <li>Becoming a university professor or researcher.</li> <li>Working in R&amp;D for global companies.</li> <li>Joining government research institutions (e.g., <a href="https://www.aist.go.jp/aist_e/humanres/">AIST</a>, <a href="https://www.riken.jp/en/careers/openings/">RIKEN</a>).</li> </ul> </li> </ul> <h2 id="preparing-for-university-admission-in-japan">Preparing for University Admission in Japan</h2> <h3 id="1-undergraduate-admission">1. Undergraduate Admission</h3> <ul> <li>Check university websites for application requirements.</li> <li>Many universities have special entrance exams for international students.</li> </ul> <h3 id="2-graduate-admission">2. Graduate Admission</h3> <ul> <li>Contact potential professors in advance (Email is always the best way to make the first contact).</li> <li>Professors or principal investigators (PIs) run research labs; obtaining their support is crucial for admission.</li> <li>Apply for scholarships early, as funding applications often start a year before enrollment.</li> <li>Some PIs allow students to join as “<strong>research students” in their laboratory</strong> before official admission.</li> </ul> <h3 id="3-finding-the-right-research-lab">3. Finding the Right Research Lab</h3> <p><strong>Useful Databases:</strong></p> <ul> <li><a href="https://researchmap.jp/?lang=en">Researchmap</a>: Japan’s largest researcher database.</li> <li><a href="https://scholar.google.com/">Google Scholar</a>: Helps track professors’ research and publications.</li> </ul> <p><strong>Understanding Lab Structures in Japan:</strong></p> <ul> <li><strong>Professor-led labs:</strong> One professor supervises all students in his laboratory.</li> <li><strong>Collaborative labs:</strong> Multiple faculty members manage one laboratory.</li> <li><strong>Roll of Assistant Professors:</strong> This role has two meanings in Japan. Although some assistant professors (tenure-track principal investigators) run their labs, most belong to specific labs and assist full/associate professors (their roles seem like postdocs). <ul> <li>Since I was a tenure-track assistant professor as a PI, I ran my own lab. Most tenure-track assistant professors have the same responsibility as full/associate professors for various duties in the university.</li> </ul> </li> </ul> <h2 id="straight-talk">Straight Talk</h2> <p>The above are general concepts. Recently, the landscape of higher education in Japan has changed significantly. Here are my comments for applicants:</p> <ul> <li> <p><strong>The Importance of Supervision Student Numbers</strong></p> <p>The number of students a professor supervises is a crucial factor. In private universities, it is common for one professor to manage 30-40 students in a lab. In national universities, however, the typical number of students per professor is 5-10, allowing for more in-depth supervision and affordable budget for your degree research.</p> </li> <li> <p><strong>Career Path After Earning a Ph.D.</strong></p> <p>Being cautious about career prospects after earning a Ph.D. is essential if you are willing to stay in Japan as a worker. In Japan, having a Ph.D. may narrow your career options (this might also be true in other countries). Therefore, many Japanese students choose to work in industry after earning a master’s degree. However, for international students, earning a Ph.D. can expand career opportunities. There are also programs where you can earn a Ph.D. while working in a company, known as “part-time Ph.D. programs for workers.”</p> </li> </ul> <h2 id="conclusion">Conclusion</h2> <p>Japan offers STEM education opportunities, but choosing the right institution requires careful planning. National and public universities are affordable and strong in research, while private universities offer modern infrastructure and industry connections. Kosen institutions are a unique pathway for hands-on technical education. Understanding the admission process and securing funding are key to a successful academic journey in Japan.</p> <ul> <li>Please share your thoughts via comment or email!</li> <li>Follow my social media (LinkedIn, X), which will provide you with the latest blog posts!</li> </ul>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="info"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Looking to study in Japan? Check out this post on Japan's higher education system and key insights for STEM students!]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Future of 3D CAD Design with Natural Language Processing</title><link href="https://ysnrski.github.io/blog/2025/The-Future-of-3D-CAD-Design-with-Natural-Language/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Future of 3D CAD Design with Natural Language Processing"/><published>2025-02-06T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-02-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://ysnrski.github.io/blog/2025/The%20Future%20of%203D%20CAD%20Design%20with%20Natural%20Language</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://ysnrski.github.io/blog/2025/The-Future-of-3D-CAD-Design-with-Natural-Language/"><![CDATA[<h1 id="the-future-of-3d-cad-design-with-natural-language-processing">The Future of 3D CAD Design with Natural Language Processing</h1> <p>In recent years, 3D CAD (Computer-Aided Design) has transformed how we approach product design and development. 3D CAD data is now the global standard for digital manufacturing, such as computer numerical control machining, computer-aided engineering (physical simulation), and 3D/4D printing. The digitalization of manufacturing enhances our work and makes it more efficient and collaborative in a globalized market.</p> <p>Although 3D CAD software must be a game-changer in manufacturing industries, engineers must spend a lot of time gaining their skills and knowledge about 3D CAD software such as Autodesk Inventor, Solidworks, and CATIA, which have different features in their operations and functions. Engineers need to learn this software separately. Sometimes, it isn’t easy to understand, even if someone has knowledge and experience with a specific software. Moreover, if someone is not in the engineering department, it tends to be challenging to operate/learn 3D CAD software from scratch.</p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/posts/20250206/key-features-of-inventor-large-1920x1038.avif" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/posts/20250206/key-features-of-inventor-large-1920x1038.avif" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <p>3D model design with Autodesk Inventor, image source: <a href="https://www.autodesk.com/eu/products/inventor/overview?term=1-YEAR&amp;tab=subscription">Autodesk</a></p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/posts/20250206/3dx-Nonlinear2520Stress-Simulation2520BioDapt-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/posts/20250206/3dx-Nonlinear2520Stress-Simulation2520BioDapt-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/posts/20250206/3dx-Nonlinear2520Stress-Simulation2520BioDapt-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/posts/20250206/3dx-Nonlinear2520Stress-Simulation2520BioDapt.jpg" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <p>Phisical Simulation (CAE) with Solidworks, image source: <a href="https://www.solidworks.com/product/structural-mechanics-engineer">Solidworks</a></p> <p>Given the current trend of ”Technological Democratization,” 3D CAD software, which has not had an unchanged user interface for 50 years, needs to redefine its user interface as everyone’s tool for manufacturing. This will activate cross-disciplinary collaboration involving more and more.</p> <p><strong>HOW DOES THE DEMOCRATIZATION OF 3DCAD SOFTWARE HAPPEN??</strong></p> <p>A new frontier is emerging—the integration of Natural Language Processing (NLP) into 3D CAD systems, thanks to the transformer architecture developed by Google researchers (<a href="https://arxiv.org/pdf/1706.03762">Ashish Vaswani et al., 2017</a>). Leading large language models (LLMs) such as BIRT (Google), GPT-4(OpenAI) and DeepSeek(DeepSeek) have the potential to revolutionize the design process, making it more intuitive, efficient, and accessible for everyone.</p> <h2 id="paradimshift-of--user-experience-with-nlp">Paradimshift of User Experience with NLP</h2> <p>As I mentioned, the design process in traditional 3D CAD systems can be complex and often requires high technical skill. However, by integrating NLP and machine learning(ML), we are moving towards a future where designers can interact with CAD systems in a more natural, conversational way. Imagine being able to describe your design concept using everyday language (any language we use) — the CAD system would then translate this into a 3D model and optimize the shape. For example, a user might say,” Create a gear with a 50mm diameter and 10 teeth,” and the system would automatically generate the corresponding 3D model.</p> <p>This shift would democratize design, allowing individuals without deep CAD expertise to bring their ideas to life. It would also increase efficiency by reducing the time spent learning and navigating complex software interfaces. Moreover, it would break the barrier between languages such as English, Chinese, and Japanese.</p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/posts/20250206/architecture-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/posts/20250206/architecture-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/posts/20250206/architecture-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/posts/20250206/architecture.png" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <p>Shape Generation Profess with large language model (LLM). Image source: <a href="https://arxiv.org/html/2406.00144v1">Akshay Badagabettu et.al.</a></p> <h2 id="streamlining-the-design-process">Streamlining the Design Process</h2> <p>Another benefit of incorporating NLP into 3D CAD is the potential to streamline the design process. NLP could be used to automate repetitive tasks, such as adjusting dimensions or converting between different units of measurement. Additionally, NLP-powered systems could detect errors by recognizing design discrepancies or inconsistencies based on the designer’s verbal input.</p> <p>Furthermore, integrating NLP with AI-driven optimized design suggestions could help designers explore new ideas more quickly. For instance, after inputting a design specification, the system could propose optimizations or variations based on best practices or historical data, providing designers with options they might not have considered.</p> <h2 id="nlp-for-collaboration">NLP for Collaboration</h2> <p>NLP could be pivotal in communication and idea sharing in collaborative design environments. Designers, engineers, and other stakeholders could communicate more effectively by speaking or typing in natural language. This would remove barriers related to technical jargon, allowing team members with different backgrounds to contribute seamlessly.</p> <p>This could benefit multidisciplinary teams, where participants may not have expertise in each other’s fields. NLP could act as a bridge/hab, enabling cross-functional teams to communicate their ideas without needing deep technical knowledge of each other’s disciplines.</p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/posts/20250206/image-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/posts/20250206/image-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/posts/20250206/image-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/posts/20250206/image.png" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <p>3D model generation example with Autodesk Inventor, image source: <a href="https://www.bing.com/ck/a?!&amp;&amp;p=afd8c3d0b68362e08066709bbc98173b33ad4390e2ad346362a4d88e09f67810JmltdHM9MTczODcxMzYwMA&amp;ptn=3&amp;ver=2&amp;hsh=4&amp;fclid=1be04c98-b7f1-6773-01b6-5f7cb6b5667d&amp;psq=NLP+Autodesk+inventor&amp;u=a1aHR0cHM6Ly9zdGF0aWMuYXUtdXcyLXByZC5hdXRvZGVzay5jb20vQVUyMDIzX01GRzYwMjcxNl9IYW5kb3V0XzE2OTg4NzE4NTk0ODgwMDFnQjZJLnBkZg&amp;ntb=1">Kivanc Kizildemir@Codeo Solutions Limited</a></p> <h2 id="future-prospects-and-challenges">Future Prospects and Challenges</h2> <p>While integrating NLP into 3D CAD systems holds exciting potential, there are still challenges to overcome. One of the biggest hurdles is ensuring the accuracy and contextual understanding of natural language inputs. CAD systems must correctly generate the intended design and interpret vague or ambiguous descriptions to generate the intended fine-tuned documents in desired fields; context recognition in expert conviction is still challenging for NLP.</p> <p>Moreover, data privacy and security concerns must be addressed, especially if sensitive design information is communicated through NLP-powered interfaces. Technology regulations due to security concerns and economic wars often disrupt technology development for businesses, especially startups. Thus we need to consider for our businesses the following:</p> <ul> <li>Could open-source NLP like GPT-J be the best option?</li> <li>Is DeepSeek a promising way (Should be affected by regulations in specific countries)?</li> <li>Should we switch NLP systems depending on the country? For China, use DeepSeek; for the U.S., use ChatGPT. (Development costs could skyrocket)</li> </ul> <p>To return to the topic… As NLP technologies evolve, we can expect even more powerful and user-friendly systems that will redefine how we approach design and product development.</p> <p>By making design tools more accessible and efficient, NLP could unlock new possibilities in industries ranging from manufacturing to healthcare, where precise and innovative design is critical.</p> <h2 id="conclusion">Conclusion</h2> <p>Natural Language Processing is poised to be a game-changer for digitalized intelligent manufacturing with 3D CAD software. The ability to interact with design systems using natural language will enhance user experience, increase productivity, and foster more inclusive collaboration. As this technology advances, it has the potential to shape the future of design and innovation in ways we are only beginning to imagine.</p> <p>NLP-based interactive assistance for 3D shape generation will provide a more efficient and collaborative working environment. What kinds of features in NLP-based design software would enable both technical and non-technical users to experience the democratization of design?</p> <h3 id="please-share-your-thoughts-via-comment-or-e-mail">Please share your thoughts via comment or e-mail!</h3> <h3 id="please-follow-my-social-media-linkedin-x-which-will-provide-you-with-the-latest-blog-posts">Please follow my social media (LinkedIn, X), which will provide you with the latest blog posts!</h3> <h2 id="references">References</h2> <ol> <li>Badagabettu, Akshay, Sai Sravan Yarlagadda, and Amir Barati Farimani “Query2CAD: Generating CAD Models Using Natural Language Queries” <em>arXiv , 2024,</em> <a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.00144">https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.00144</a></li> <li>Kung, Chuei-Huei, and Kuei-Chia Liang.”Exploring the Usability and Future Development of AI-Generated 3D Models in CAD Workflows and the Metaverse Based on 3D Model Standards” <em>Computer-Aided Design and Applications</em>, 782–804, 2025, <a href="http://dx.doi.org/10.14733/cadaps.2025.782-804">http://dx.doi.org/10.14733/cadaps.2025.782-804</a></li> <li>David J Kasik, William Buxton, and David R Ferguson. Ten cad challenges. IEEE Computer Graphics and Applications, 25(2):81–92, 2005, <a href="https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/1405956/">https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/1405956/</a></li> </ol>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="trend"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Explore how NLP is revolutionizing 3D CAD design, making it more accessible, efficient, and intuitive. From automating repetitive tasks to enabling cross-disciplinary collaboration, discover how NLP is reshaping the future of digital manufacturing.]]></summary></entry></feed>